- Hi, I'm Kelly with Microsoft.
And today we are broadcasting live
from the United Kingdom's RC Racetrack
to our global audience.
Creating compelling live events may appear simple
but production teams know all too well
the complexities in delivering these experiences.
Integrating and operating technical systems,
applications, networks, and onsite personnel
can be daunting as well as costly and time consuming.
Microsoft's digital experience solution
helps to simplify the delivery of live events
by removing these complexities
while also reducing required onsite personnel.
Microsoft has partnered with industry leading vendors,
Evertz, MediaKind and Lumen
to provide a pre-integrated global solution
that scales for events of any size.
The live events process consists of five phases.
Ingest, produce, prepare, distribute, and experience.
These phases span the workflow
from the point of media acquisition
to the in consumer experience on a consumer device.
Each partner plays an important role
in delivering the live event.
This solution also spans multiple locations,
both geographical and virtual,
from the racetrack to Microsoft's Azure cloud,
to the consumer's device.
The workflow commences with MediaKind
acquiring and encoding media from the event location.
The media is then delivered
across a Lumen contribution network
to Evertz's Bravo studio running in Azure.
From there, the raw feeds are mixed together
and the produced output streams
are pushed to MediaKind's Aquila platform,
where they are processed and prepared
for consumer consumption.
The prepared streams are subsequently delivered
across Lumens content delivery network
to the consumer device of choice.
Let's break the solution down,
beginning with Evertz.
Evertz Bravo Studio is a cloud first
virtual production platform
serving as a production studio for our live events.
Residing in the Azure cloud,
Bravo Studio is a collection of resources
you can find in traditional production workflows.
Its simple, intuitive interface
can be used by any production to collaborate from anywhere.
Bravo Studios mixes together raw feeds
as well as additional content to create a produced stream
for the intended audience.
Let's get back to the track and see Bravo Studio in action.
We have six sources of raw media
and the output for the produced stream displayed.
The sources are comprised of four camera feeds at the track,
our announcer, who is offsite using Microsoft Teams,
and a graphics club.
Through this interface, we can select any source,
preview it, take a transition
and output the result to air.
Watch as we easily switch between the different angles
at the track.
We can also switch audio and overlays here.
We overlay our announcers audio
onto the races video feeds to deliver the commentary.
Audio of course requires the ability
to manipulate the audio levels.
Here have an audio mixer which allows us
to alter the announcer's voice
as well as audio coming from the track
to create a pleasing experience for the viewer.
With Bravo Studio,
we can spruce up our production with graphics.
In this case,
we can use a transition to return to the action.
Bravo studio uses co-pilots
to simplify the production workflow for the operators.
We have created a storyboard comprised of three components,
the graphic, transition, and ultimately the camera angle
we wish to use upon completion of the segment
in the rundown.
Let's take this to air and we'll see the graphics countdown
followed by the transition and the live camera feed.
In this demonstration,
we've shown several of Bravo Studio's
virtual production capabilities
that result in a stream ready for distribution.
This stream can be sent either to MediaKind
for distribution to our consumer's favorite digital device,
or to a Microsoft Teams live event
where you may want to support a watch party
or include it in a meeting or presentation.
MediaKind's Aquila is a cloud native broadcast quality
OTT streaming as a service platform.
It provides content processing, streaming services,
and enables media monetization.
This robust service is built on Microsoft's Azure cloud
and simplifies the configuration and integration
associated with media processing and streaming.
It also dynamically allocates and scales resources
depending on the workload,
allowing for cost optimizations across both Aquila software
and the infrastructure it resides within.
Aquila can be deployed in any Azure region,
providing the services you need where you need them.
Lastly, MediaKind's technology can reduce network bandwidth,
player latency, and content delivery network file caching,
thereby improving the consumer's experience
and lowering your operating cost.
Let's use Aquila to create a channel
for our racetrack event.
Starting with a homepage,
we see a list of the streaming channels
representing our racetrack camera angles already running.
The green check mark indicates the channel is running
and there are no alarms.
For each channel, you can see the templates,
source, and Azure region being used.
To create our produced stream,
we must first create a source and then a channel.
From the source screen,
we define a name, input mode, and Azure region
where the source will reside,
and then click add new.
Once the source is created,
the IP address and port information are available.
These will be used by Bravo Studio
to send the produced stream
into the appropriate MediaKind source.
Next, let's create a channel.
From the create channel screen,
we define a new channel name
and select the source we just created.
We then select a template
from the desired preset channel configuration.
In this case, we opt for a standard template.
Templates make it easy to spin up multiple channels
with the same configuration
by predefining the channel's attributes.
A default set of templates is included
and additional customized templates
can be easily added by the customer.
Although we've created our channel,
nothing has been provisioned
within the Azure environment yet.
To provision the channel,
the activate or play button is selected,
and the necessary services are deployed into Azure
where they are configured based on our template.
The entire process is fully automated,
and once complete the URLs for the adaptive bit rate streams
are available.
Here we see our channel stream and corresponding URL.
Aquila also supports dynamic ad insertion and blackouts.
Let's demonstrate this manually using this view
where we see multiple streams of the produced content.
The largest window in the top left corner
is showing the video being pulled from the origin,
bypassing the personalization service
that's used for ad insertion and blackouts.
The six streams on the bottom
are all coming from the personalization service,
each representing an audience that is being targeted
or blacked out based on geographic region and interest.
By clicking the ad button,
we instruct the platform to insert an ad signal
into the stream in real time,
indicating the start of an ad break
with a duration of 10 seconds.
Each audience will receive a different ad
determined by the ad decisioning server
based on their location and interest.
Some content licensing will require blackouts
to be enforced for a portion of the audience.
In our case, it's based on geography.
Clicking on the blackout button
instruct the platform to insert a different signal
into the stream,
indicating the start of the program to be blacked out.
For a demonstration,
our blackout has a duration of 10 seconds
and as being applied to the Florida zone one region.
So all viewers in that region will get the same slate
indicating their region is blacked out.
The rest of our audience
will continue to receive our racetrack event.
We now have a produced stream ready for distribution
across a global audience
with personalized ads inserted
and geographic blackouts enforced.
- As we mentioned earlier,
this is a a geographically dispersed production
that includes an event location, Microsoft's Azure cloud,
and audience members around the globe.
Broadcasts of this type require low latency networks
to deliver the signal across many discreet locations.
For our car race,
Lumen provides the signal acquisition network Vyvx
for contribution from the event location
to Microsoft's Azure cloud,
as well as the content delivery network
from Microsoft's cloud to the audience.
The network is designed to deliver
reliable low latency connectivity
to help ensure the timely delivery of media
across the camera to consumption workflow.
Lumen's Vyvx Venue Net is installed on premises
at over 240 stadiums and event venues today.
It includes dedicated encoding equipment
and managed video network services
with high capacity fiber connections to the Lumen backbone.
Vyvx offers white glove fully managed services
for high profile events worldwide,
with zero tolerance for failure.
The service includes 24/7 booking,
a customer care center,
and self-service portals
to support video delivery anytime and virtually anywhere.
Lumen's content distribution flow begins in the Azure cloud
where the produced streams
can be distributed to multiple types of outlets.
Distribution to television outlets
and multi value programming distributors
typically leverages either the Vyvx fiber network
or teleport services
which are used to reach outlets
not on the Vyvx fiber network.
Alternatively, the Lumen CDN
provides OTT streaming capabilities to online viewers
leveraging Lumen's global IP network backbone
and strong ISP peering relationships
to deliver best in class streaming experiences.
One of the largest CDNs in the world,
the Lumen content delivery network,
is globally architect for high availability and low latency.
Its security features include
encrypted delivery over the network
and active monitoring to mitigate security threats.
Additionally, the Lumen CDN can be augmented
with their peer assisted mesh delivery
to enhance quality of service,
increase reach,
and enable reliable scaling for flash crowds
during high traffic events.
- Microsoft's Azure cloud is the public cloud
providing the compute, storage, networking and data
to power the solution.
Azure enables producers to dynamically stand up their events
where, and when they need them.
It has the largest geographical footprint
of any cloud provider today,
with over 60 regions, 200 data centers,
and 4 million servers worldwide.
For resiliency, regions are comprised of availability zones
which are data centers geographically close to one another
that have been designed to have no single point of failure.
Azure services such as data and compute
contain built in resiliency orchestration services.
Microsoft is also doing our part
to build a sustainable future.
We are making a commitment to be carbon negative by 2030
and to move our historical impact by 2050.
Microsoft's progress benefits you
because we emit 98% less CO2
and use 93% less energy than on-premises data centers today.
This live event solution
further enables a virtualized production team
to reduce their CO2 footprints.
Equally concerning are the security issues we are facing
from malicious actors,
whether they are nation states or individuals.
Microsoft's identity and access management platform,
Active Directory,
is a key component of an effective security policy.
And it's used by over 90% of Fortune 500 companies today.
with Active Directory, you will have single identity
spanning all of your applications,
including Evertz Bravo Studio,
MediaKind's Aquila and Lumen networks.
Further authorization can be hardened
with multifactor authentication.
AD works for applications both in the cloud and on premise,
enabling universal access to every application.
Microsoft's live event solution
offers four key benefits to producers.
First, this pre-integrated solution
provides a comprehensive set of capabilities
spanning the full camera to OTT workflow
removing operational complexities
and enabling you to focus on being creative.
Second, turnkey operations are enabled
by combining Evertz, MediaKind, Lumen
and Microsoft's highly scalable, low latency,
broadcast ready and globally accessible capabilities
in a convenient pay as you go model.
Third, this solution delivers simplified provisioning
to enable faster time to value
and is offered in both self support
and managed service models.
Lastly, the solution is secured
using Microsoft's identity management platform
to support a single identity
across each of the applications.
Further multi factor authentication
helps safeguard access to data and applications
while meeting user demand for a simple sign in process.
Microsoft has set ambitious sustainability goals
and has been focused on both emissions
and natural resource usage.
Our leadership in these areas
translates into our customers reaping benefits
when they use Microsoft Cloud.
This concludes our live event from the racetrack today.